Thank you, Sister Wan'er
婉儿ちゃんありがとう
Risking yourself to save us, mother and son
私たち親子を救うために危険を顧みない
A transaction
ひとつの取引
Each has their needs
人それぞれ求めるものがある
But I cannot go with you
でも私はあなたと一緒に行けません
Why?
どういう理由ですか
I am Prince Ning's
私は寧王です
Most important trump card to threaten Your Highness
殿下を脅かすための最も重要な切り札
If the prince and I both disappear
もし私が世子と一緒に失踪したら
Prince Ning will search everywhere
寧王は地面を三尺掘った
And find us
私たちを見つけ出してしまうこともあるでしょう
By then
その時に
Not only will we not be safe
私たちは守れないばかりか
But you will also lose your life
あなたの命まで奪うかもしれない
Only if I stay
私だけが残った
Will Prince Ning think his trump card remains
寧王だけが自分の切り札はまだ残っていると感じるだろう
Take the prince away
世子を連れて行け
Take good care of him
彼の世話をしてあげてください
Thank you
ありがとう
March of the 24th year of Yuankang
元康二十四年三月
Prince of Jin Sikong Yao led a great army to attack the capital Nandu
晋の王である司空耀は大軍を率いて京城南都を攻撃した
Facing this northern expedition army
この北伐軍に直面して
Nandu's defenders were powerless to resist
南都城の守備軍は抵抗する力がない
After one day
一日後
Nandu fell
南都城破れる
Xie Xuan
謝玄
Where is your sister?
あなたのお姉さんは
Where is she?
彼女はどこですか
I'm asking you, where is your sister?
あなたのお姉さんはどこですか
Miss
お嬢さん
Why do you look so worried?
どうしてそんなにしかめっ面をしているの
Father insists I marry a prince
父はどうしても私を王子に嫁がせたがっている
I know
私は知っています
Father has his reasons
お父さんには彼なりの考えがある
But I've never even met this Prince of Jin
でもこの晋の王には私は面会したこともありません
I really don't want to marry so blindly
私はこんなにいい加減に結婚したくない
How about
それとも
I write you a note
私があなたにメモを書いてあげます
Owed to my wife
欠けた夫人
Willow picking at Ba
灞上で柳を折る
Flower viewing at Yong'an
永安で花見
Kill
殺す
This is just my letter home
これはただ私の家への手紙です
Why was it opened?
なぜ人に壊されたのですか
This edict is fake
この勅命は偽物です
First wish
一つの願い
Long live my husband
旦那様万歳
Second wish
二つの誓願
The prince always healthy
世子は常に健康です
Third wish
三つの願い
Become swallows on the beam
梁の上の燕に変わる
Year after year
年々
Always together
よく会う
Ruolan
ルーラン
Yong'an flowers
永安花
This debt
この借金
I cannot collect
私はもう取り戻せません
Ruolan
ルーラン
Prince of Jin Sikong Yao
晋の王司空耀
Seeing me
私に会う
Why don't you kneel?
まだひざまずかない
Drag him down for me
彼を私のところに引き下ろして
How dare you
図々しい
You
あなたたち
It was you
あなたです
Who drove Ruolan to death
若兰を追い詰めた
Sister-in-law
弟と妹
Sister-in-law, to avoid becoming
弟妹は〜にならないために
My leverage against you
私はあなたの弱みを脅しています
Already took her own life first
とっくに自殺してしまった
It was you
あなたです
Your ambition
それはあなたの野心です
Killed her
彼女を死なせてしまった
What?
どう
Thinking how to kill me?
どうやって殺すか考えていた
To ease the guilt in your heart?
あなたの心の中の罪悪感を理解しています
Let me think
ちょっと考えさせて
How will historians record you?
史官はあなたをどう記録するだろうか
Brothers fighting
同じ屋根の下で争う
Killing brother to seize the throne
兄を殺して位を奪う
Yao'er
ヨウアル
Yao'er, stop
耀児やめて
Your elder brother spared you once
最初あなたのお兄さんはあなたを一度見逃してくれました
Mother begs you
娘お願いだから
Spare him this time
今回だけは彼を許してあげて
You are flesh and blood brothers
あなたたちは血のつながった兄弟ですね
Yao'er
ヨウアー